Stephen J. Gould papers M1437
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 5: Audiovisual Materials
  - Steve Gould: Size and Shape in Biology, 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette; 60 min. (Box 431, Audiocassettes 87)
  - Wedns. - Mesoges (sic) from a. Mach., 4/1989; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette; 90 min. (Box 431, Audiocassettes 88)
  - Dr. Gould, nd; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette (Box 431, Audiocassettes 89)
  - Don Giovanni at Dahlem, nd; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette; 90 min. (Box 431, Audiocassettes 90)
  - Hist., 12/1981; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette (Box 431, Audiocassettes 91)
  - Arrested Development: 3 years, 5 months and 2 days in the Life of Mylene Farmer and Francois Feldman, 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette; 110 min. (Box 431, Audiocassettes 92)
  - Talmud Tape 1, pages 3-9, 9/2000; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette; 90 min. (Box 432, Audiocassettes 1)
  - (2) SJG 4th-6th, nd; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette; 60 min. (Box 432, Audiocassettes 2)
  - Stewart/Gould 12-1, 12/1989; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette (Box 432, Audiocassettes 3)
  - SJG National Public Radio, 11/1989; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette; 90 min. (Box 432, Audiocassettes 4)
  - #624 Darwinian Dialogue, 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette (Box 432, Audiocassettes 5)
  - Science Show #200, 1/1980; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette; 90 min. (Box 432, Audiocassettes 6)
  - SJG - "Today Show", 12/1989; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette; 90 min. (Box 432, Audiocassettes 7)
  - SJG - "Larry King Live", 12/1989; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette; 90 min. (Box 432, Audiocassettes 8)
  - SJG - Bookmark, 12/1989; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette; 100 min. (Box 432, Audiocassettes 9)
  - From Mud to Man, nd; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette; 60 min. (Box 432, Audiocassettes 10)
  - Stephen Jay Gould in conversation with Colin Tudge, nd; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette; 90 min. (Box 432, Audiocassettes 11)
  - Law School: Steve Gould Tapes 1-2, 4/1986; 2.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassettes; 90 min. each (Box 432, Audiocassettes 12-13)
  - How Science Works "Roots Writ Large", nd; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette; 60 min. (Box 432, Audiocassettes 14)
  - National Center for Science Education Annual Meeting, 2/1988; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette; 90 min. (Box 432, Audiocassettes 15)
  - Science Show #624 "Darwiniam Dialogue", 3/1988; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette; 90 min. (Box 432, Audiocassettes 16)
  - S. Gould Side 1, nd; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette (Box 432, Audiocassettes 17)
  - JBS Stephen Jay Gould 12-1, 5/1991; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette (Box 432, Audiocassettes 18)
  - Aujorer d'hui la Science, 10/1983; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette; 60 min. (Box 432, Audiocassettes 19)
  - New Lamps for Old… Tape 3, 5/1990; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette (Box 432, Audiocassettes 20)
  - Stephen Jay Gould - American Museum of Natural History, 11/1978; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette (Box 432, Audiocassettes 21)
  - Steven Gould (sic), nd; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette; 60 min. (Box 432, Audiocassettes 22)
  - [untitled Memorex Tape], nd; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape cassette; 90 min. (Box 432, Audiocassettes 23)
  - [five untitled audio microcassettes], nd; 5.0 Items; Audio: 1/8" microcassettes (5); 60 min. each (Box 432, Audiocassettes 24-28)
  - [Stenorette Magazines #1 and #2], 2.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiotape in magazines; unknown lengths (Box 432, Othercontainertype 29-30)
  - Gould, Class = 84, 1984; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" reel to reel audiotape; 5" reel (Box 432, Reel 31)
  - Winchell Series: Dr. Gould Lecture, nd; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" reel to reel audiotape; 7" reel (Box 432, Reel 32)
  - [untitled 1/4" audiotape reel], nd; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" reel to reel audiotape; 7" reel (Box 432, Reel 33)
  - Jay Gould at Society of Zoologists Philadelphia '84, nd; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" reel to reel audiotape; 7" reel (Box 432, Reel 34)
  - Gould S.R. 1-2 Transcript, nd; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" reel to reel audiotape; 7" reel (Box 432, Reel 35)
  - Memoirs of the Future: Reflections from the TED3 Conference, 1992; 1.0 Items; Audio: Compact Disc (Box 432, Othercontainertype 36)
  - Entrez: Sequences, 1992; 1.0 Items; Computer Media: CD Data Disc (Box 432, Cd-rom 37)
  - Windows Programs - Exams Unlimited, Inc. Key Diskette, 1.0 Items; Computer Media: 3.5" Diskette (Box 432, Diskette 38)
  - Evolution (2 copies), 2001; 2.0 Items; Computer Media: CD-ROM (Box 432, Cd-rom 39-40)
  - Gould - American Museum, nd; 1.0 Items; Film: 16mm Color sound positive (Box 432, Reel 41)
  - Steve Gould, nd; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" reel to reel audiotape; 5" reel (Box 432, Reel 42)
  - Sony BM-550 Microcassette Dictator in protective case, nd; 1.0 Items (Box 432, Object 43)
  - Kennst du das Land, 1.0 Items; object - empty audiocassette tape case with possibly hand-designed cover (Box 432, Object 44)
  - SJ Gould Interview, 8/1973; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiocassette; 90 min. (Box 433, Audiocassettes 1)
  - The Jim Bohannon Show: Stephen Gould 11-12: January 1996, 1/1996; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiocassette; 60 min. (Box 433, Audiocassettes 2)
  - The Jim Bohannon Show: SJ Gould 10-11: March 1999, 3/1999; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiocassette; 60 min. (Box 433, Audiocassettes 3)
  - The Jim Bohannon Show: Stephen Jay Gould 10-11: August 1999, 8/1999; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiocassette; 60 min. (Box 433, Audiocassettes 4)
  - The Jim Bohannon Show: S.J. Gould 10-11: January 2000, 1/2000; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiocassette; 60 min. (Box 433, Audiocassettes 5)
  - Diane Rehna (?), SJG on WAMU, 1/1996; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiocassette (Box 433, Audiocassettes 6)
  - 90.9 WBUR: Connection Gould, 6/1996; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiocassette; 120 min. (Box 433, Audiocassettes 7)
  - Stephen Jay Gould: "Full House" - The Commonwealth Club of California, 9/1996; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiocassette (Box 433, Audiocassettes 8)
  - Stephen Jay Gould on "The Green Room with Dorian" - 91.1 WFMU, 9/1996; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiocassette; 60 min. (Box 433, Audiocassettes 9)
  - Studs Terkel with Stephen J. Gould - 98.7 WFMT Chicago, 10/1996; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiocassette (Box 433, Audiocassettes 10)
  - Stephen J Gould on WNYC: October 1996, 10/1996; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiocassette; 90 min. (Box 433, Audiocassettes 11)
  - Stephen Jay Gould on WNYC: No Date, nd; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiocassette; 90 min. (Box 433, Audiocassettes 12)
  - Osgood File: SJG on Y2K, 10/1997; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiocassette; 60 min. (Box 433, Audiocassettes 13)
  - SJG on WAMU: Y2K, nd; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiocassette (Box 433, Audiocassettes 14)
  - SJG on WWDC Radio on Y2K, nd; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/4" audiocassette (Box 433, Audiocassettes 15)
  - Tape 1, nd; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/8" microcassette; 60 min. (Box 433, Audiocassettes 16)
  - Tape 2, nd; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/8" microcassette; 60 min. (Box 433, Audiocassettes 17)
  - [3 untitled microcassettes], nd; 1.0 Items; Audio: 1/8" microcassette; 90 min. each (Box 433, Audiocassettes 18-20)
  - SJG on "60 Minutes" - February 1984, 2/1984; 1.0 Items; Video: Dub; VHS; 30 min. (Box 433, Audiocassettes 21)
  - Jesse's Graduation - June 1992, 6/1992; 1.0 Items; Video: Dub; VHS; 120 min. (Box 433, Audiocassettes 22)
  - [JVC compact VHS cassette adapter], nd; 1.0 Items; object (Box 433, Audiocassettes 23)
  - Allen and Jones: April 1987, 4/1987; 1.0 Items; Video: Dub; Betacam (Box 433, Audiocassettes 24)
  - Horizons Cable Network Promotional Tape, nd; 1.0 Items; Video: Dub; VHS; 00:09:01 (Box 433, Audiocassettes 25)
  - "Sixty Minutes": April 1984, 4/1984; 1.0 Items; Video: Dub; Betacam (Box 433, Audiocassettes 26)
  - Peter Gould - Tony Awards, nd; 1.0 Items; Video: Dub; VHS; 120 min. (Box 433, Audiocassettes 27)
  - In Search of History - Episode #H104 "The Monkey Trial", nd; 1.0 Items; Video: Dub; VHS; 30 min. (Box 433, Audiocassettes 28)
  - Jesse's Violin Concert: May 1990, 5/1990; 1.0 Items; Video: Dub; VHS; 120 min. (Box 433, Audiocassettes 29)
  - Jesse's Third Violin Concert: June 1991, 6/1991; 1.0 Items; Video: Dub; VHS; 120 min. (Box 433, Audiocassettes 30)
  - Jesse's Violin Concert: June 1992, 6/1992; 1.0 Items; Video: Dub; VHS; 120 min. (Box 433, Audiocassettes 31)
  - Jesse's Violin Concert: August 1993, 8/1993; 1.0 Items; Video: Dub; VHS; 120 min. (Box 433, Audiocassettes 32)
  - Jesse's Violin Concert: August 1994, 8/1994; 1.0 Items; Video: Dub; VHS; 120 min. (Box 433, Audiocassettes 33)
- Series 6: Born Digital Materials, 1979-2002; 52.0 megabytes (1,180 computer files)
  This series consists primarily of the born digital material from the Stephen Jay Gould (SJG) papers. The born digital material was stored in floppy diskettes, tapes and punch cards. The labels, if any, on the computer media are in many cases too brief to tell the contents in the diskettes. The processor viewed the contents of the files to using AccessData's FTK software to decide the proper EAD component levels which the contents belong to. The processor followed the arrangement used in processing the paper component of Gould's collection for the most part. Details of the ten subseries are as follows.
  Arrangement note
  The computer files (895) are described in 9 subseries: Subseries I, Articles, contains 99 files; Subseries II, Abstracts, Reviews, Letters, etc., contains 107 files; Subseries III, Natural History Column, contains 171 files; Subseries IV, Books, contains drafts of 12 books written by SJG: The Structure of Evolutionary Theory, Full House, The Book of Life, Triumph and Tragedy in Mudville, Dinosaur in a Haystack, The Burgess Series VI: Shale and the Nature of History, Time's Arrow, time's Cycle, The Lying Stones of Marrakech, Eight Little Piggies, Hidden Histories of Science, The Hedgehog, the Fox, and the Magister’s Pox, The Mismeasure of Man - there are 404 files in this subseries; Subseries V, Bibliography & CV, contains several versions of bibliography and CV of SJG - there are 44 files in this subseries; Subseries VI, Teaching, contains examination papers, syllabus, and student lists. There are 12 files in this subseries; Subseries VII, Rare Books, contains information on the rare books owned by SJG - there are 28 files in this subseries; Subseries VIII, Punch Cards, contains computer programs and data migrated from one box of punch cards. Data in another box of punch cards is not migrated - there are 11 files in this subseries; Subseries IX, Miscellaneous, is divided into 3 sub-subseries: National Science Foundation (NSF) contains documents on NSF grants; Paleontological Society contains correspondence related to the Society; and Others - there are 18 files in this subseries.
  Subseries X, Computer Media Photos, contains photos of the punch cards, tapes, 5.25 inch floppy and 3.5 inch floppy diskettes taken by the processor. There are 165 hand-held items in this subseries.
- Series 7: Other Material
  - Academic Regalia
    - Academic Regalia (Cartons 316-317)
    - Academic Regalia (Cartons 321-324)
    - Academic Regalia (Carton 364)
  - Artifacts
    - Geological survey tools & musical instruments (Carton 412)
    - Framed artwork (Carton 413)
    - Sculpture (Carton 414)
    - Sculpture (Carton 416)
  - Awards
    - Awards (medals) (Carton 240)
    - Awards (certificates, honorary degrees, plaques) (Carton 245)
    - Awards (certificates, honorary degrees) (Carton 307)
    - Awards (certificates, honorary degrees, plaques) (Cartons 308-309)
    - Awards (plaques and other commemorative objects) (Carton 357)
    - Awards (certificates, honorary degrees, plaques) (Carton 392)
    - Awards (certificates, honorary degrees) (Flat-box 438, Folders 4-6)
    - Awards (certificates, honorary degrees) (Flat-box 518, Folder 6)
    - Awards (plaques and other commemorative objects) (Carton 555)
    - Awards (plaques and other commemorative objects) (Flat-box 558)
  - Baseball
    - Baseball Clippings (Flat-box 514, Folder 7)
    - Baseball - Data about .400 Hitting (Flat-box 514, Folder 6)
    - Baseball Ephemera (Miscellaneous) (Flat-box 514, Folder 8)
    - Baseball publications and journals (Box 519)
  - Clothing
    - T-shirts (Cartons 318-319)
    - Gould's baby clothing (Carton 415)
  - Conference, Lecture, and Sypmosia Material
    - 9th Annual Family Therapy Network Symposium: Success in Family Therapy, Washington, D. C., 1986 (Box 439, Folder 1)
    - Abertura do Congresso: Antropologia e suas fronteiras (Box 439, Folder 2)
    - Alumni Day, Harvard University, 1991 (Box 439, Folder 3)
    - Antioch College Alumni Lecture Series: An Evening with Stephen Jay Gould '63, 1991 (Box 439, Folder 4)
    - Assembly Series, Washington University in St. Louis, 1985-1986 (Box 439, Folder 5)
    - Astronomy and Space Sciences Symposium, Cornell University, 1994 (Box 439, Folder 6)
    - Baseball and the Course of American Society, 1991 (Box 439, Folder 7)
    - A Bash for Bob: In Honor of Robert M. Linsley, 1992 (Box 439, Folder 8)
    - BBN Guest Lecture Series, 1984 (Box 439, Folder 9)
    - Berea College Commencement, 1994 (Box 439, Folder 10)
    - The Boston 400 Forum, Boston Public Library, 1997 (Box 439, Folder 11)
    - Boston Colloquium for the Philosophy of Science: The Elusive Synthesis, Boston University (Box 439, Folder 12)
    - Brecht Forum: Misusing Darwin, New York (Box 439, Folder 13)
    - Brown Symposium: Punctuated Evolution, Southwestern University (Georgetown, Texas), 1990 (Box 439, Folder 14)
    - Capital Science Lectures, Carnegie Institute of Washington, 1992-1993 (Box 439, Folder 15)
    - Celebration: A Celebration of Benjamin Franklin's 294th Birthday and the Franklin Institute's 175th Anniversary, The Franklin Institute, 2000 (Box 439, Folder 16)
    - Celeste Bartos Forum, New York Public Library, 1992-1994 (Box 439, Folder 17)
    - Centennial Speakers Series: Education and Inspiration, University of New Mexico, 1992 (Box 439, Folder 18)
    - Charles Darwin's Revolution in Thought, Natural History Museum (London), 1995 (Box 439, Folder 19)
    - Ciencias Naturales, Residencia de Estudiantes, 1989 (Box 439, Folder 20)
    - Commencement, American University, 1991 (Box 439, Folder 21)
    - Daring Diversity, South Puget Sound Community College, 1991 (Box 439, Folder 22)
    - Darwin Festival, Salem State College, 1992 (Box 441, Folder 1)
    - Darwin Lecture Series on Evolution, 1995 (Box 439, Folder 23)
    - Dennis Diderot, Universite Paris (2 folders), 1994 (Box-folder 441-2, Box-folder 441-3)
    - Distinguished Lecture Series, Wisconsin Union Theater, 1994 (Box 439, Folder 24)
    - The Distinguished Scientist Lecture Series, American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 439, Folder 25)
    - Distinguished Scientists Lecture Series, Trinity University, 1991-1992 (Box 439, Folder 26)
    - Distinguished Speaker Series, University of California, Davis, 1999 (Box 439, Folder 27)
    - E. Claiborne Robins Distinguished Lecture Series in Science, University of Richmond, 1991-1992 (Box 439, Folder 28)
    - Eight Little Piggies speaking engagement (Box 439, Folder 29)
    - European Molecular Biology Laboratory (EMBL) Forum, Heidelburg, 1996 (Box 441, Folder 4)
    - Fanfare, Southeastern University, 1991 (Box 439, Folder 30)
    - Freshman Forum, Syracuse University, 1997 (Box 439, Folder 31)
    - The Graduate Council Colloquium, Wayne State University, 1998 (Box 439, Folder 32)
    - The Guy E. Van Demark Lecture Series, Augustana College, 1986-1989 (Box 439, Folder 33)
    - The History of Life and How It Helps Us Understand Today's Environmental Crisis, sponsored by Congressman Chet Atkins (Box 439, Folder 34)
    - The Homer W. Smith Visiting Professorship Lecture, New York University Medical Center, 1992 (Box 439, Folder 35)
    - Human Equality as a Contingent Fact of History, University of Arkansas for Medical Sciences (Box 439, Folder 36)
    - Indiana Molecular Biology Symposium VIII, Indiana University (Bloomington), abstracts +brochures/travel guides, 1994 (Box 439, Folder 37)
    - Intellectuals: Who Needs Them?, University of Illinois, 2002 (Box 439, Folder 38)
    - The J. Leo Dowd and Catherine Mellon Dowd Lecture Series, Monument Mountain Region HIgh School, 1998-1999 (Box 439, Folder 39)
    - John Calvin McNair Lecture, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, 1994 (Box 439, Folder 40)
    - John P. McGovern Award Lecture Series, 1993 (Box 439, Folder 41)
    - Judge Joe J. Fisher Distinguished Lecture Series, Lamar University-Beaumont, 1989 (Box 439, Folder 42)
    - Kennedy Lecture Series, Ohio University, 1992-1993 (Box 439, Folder 43)
    - Klopsteg Lecture: Why Progress Does Not Rule the History of Life (and Why No One Hits .400 Anymore), Northwestern University, 1993 (Box 439, Folder 44)
    - The Last Word Lunchtime Lectures, Royal Geographical Society London, 1997 (Box 439, Folder 45)
    - Laureation Addresses, University of St Andrews, 1993 (Box 439, Folder 46)
    - Lecture transcript, UNESCO, 1995 (Box 439, Folder 47)
    - Lifetime Achievement Award Honoring Betty Friedan, The National Arts Club (New York), 1999 (Box 439, Folder 48)
    - Literary Lights, Boston Public Library, 1990 (Box 439, Folder 49)
    - Lowell Lectures - Washburn Series, Museum of Science (Boston), 1984 (Box 440, Folder 1)
    - Luck and Pattern in the History of Life, Grand Canyon National Park, 1991 (Box 440, Folder 2)
    - Lyell Meeting, Geological Society (Burlington House, Piccadilly, London), 1995 (Box 440, Folder 3)
    - The Magill Lecture in Science, Technology and the Arts, Colombia University, 1996 (Box 440, Folder 4)
    - Martin W. Witte Distinguished Speakers Lecture Series, Newport Beach Public Library, 2000 (Box 440, Folder 5)
    - Master Scholars Programs, New York University School of Medicine, 2000 (Box 440, Folder 6)
    - Mechanical Marvels, World Finance Center, 1997-1998 (Box 440, Folder 7)
    - Merritt-Putnam Lectures, NYU-Mt. Sinai Medical Center, 2000 (Box 440, Folder 8)
    - Mickey Myths, Society for the Arts, Religion and Contemporary Culture, 1990 (Box 440, Folder 9)
    - Millennium Series, Texas Union Council, 1999 (Box 440, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous speaking engagment flyers (Box 440, Folder 11)
    - A Morning on the Millennium, New York University, 2000 (Box 440, Folder 12)
    - Muratec Human Talk, Kyoto, 1993 (Box 440, Folder 13)
    - Necessity, Contingency, and Progress in Evolution, California Academy of Sciences, 1992 (Box 440, Folder 14)
    - New Mexico State University Speaker Series: Human Equality (Box 440, Folder 15)
    - NIST Colloquium Series: The Improbability of Human Evolution in the Age of Bacteria, 1996 (Box 440, Folder 16)
    - One Hundred and Forty-Fourth Commencement, Antioch College, 1996 (Box 440, Folder 17)
    - Orations, University of Leicester, 1995 (Box 440, Folder 18)
    - Our Place in Nature, The Royal Institution (London), 1994 (Box 440, Folder 19)
    - Pisart Vision Award, 1994 (Box 440, Folder 20)
    - Portland Arts and Lectures Series, 2000-2001 (Box 440, Folder 21)
    - Public Radio Bookshow, State University of New York (Box 440, Folder 22)
    - Race & Equality, University of New Mexico (Box 440, Folder 23)
    - The Relationship of Ontogeny and Phylogeny, Geological Society of London, 1971 (Box 440, Folder 24)
    - Riders Wanted: Leaving On a 90-minute Journey Through 300 Million Years of Time, 1998-1999 (Box 440, Folder 25)
    - Saint Louis Literary Awards, Saint Louis University, 1994 (Box 440, Folder 26)
    - Science College Public Lecture Series, Concordia University, 1982 (Box 441, Folder 5)
    - The Search for Meaning, Lifeline Center (New York), 2000 (Box 440, Folder 27)
    - Seattle Arts and Lectures Literary Lecture Series, 2001-2002 (Box 440, Folder 28)
    - The Second Annual Isaac Asimove Memorial Lecture, New York Area Skeptics, 1995 (Box 440, Folder 29)
    - The SMU Willis M. Tate Distinguished Lecture Series, Southern Methodist University, 2000 (Box 440, Folder 30)
    - Sol Feinstone Lecture, 1996 (Box 440, Folder 31)
    - Spring Lecture Series: The Eye of the Beholder, Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum, 1991 (Box 440, Folder 32)
    - Stephen Jay Gould: The Fact of Evolution and the Politics of Creationism, Western Michigan University, 1994 (Box 440, Folder 33)
    - Stephen Jay Gould: Geological Immensity and Human Insignificance, Lindsay Wildlife Museum (Box 440, Folder 34)
    - Stephen Jay Gould: In the Theater of the Mind, Arcosanti, Arizonia, 1992 (Box 440, Folder 35)
    - Stephen Jay Gould - On Campus, Eckerd College (Box 440, Folder 36)
    - Stephen Jay Gould: Pattern and predictability in the history of life, Anatomisch-Embryologisch Laboratorium (Leiden) (Box 440, Folder 37)
    - Symposium on Anti-Semitism and Racism, 1994 (Box 440, Folder 38)
    - Systematics Discussion Group, American Museum of Natural History, 1985-1986 (Box 440, Folder 39)
    - The Tenth Annual Frank G. and Jean M. Chesley Lectureship, Carleton College, 1996 (Box 440, Folder 40)
    - Three Rivers Lecture Series, in association with Carnegie Library of Pittsburgh, 1996-1997 (Box 440, Folder 41)
    - Third Math-Sci Computer Symposium, Jamacia High School, 1986 (Box 441, Folder 6)
    - Twenty-five Year Recognition Ceremony, Harvard University, 1992 (Box 440, Folder 42)
    - USC Spectrum Distinguished Lecture Series (Box 440, Folder 43)
    - The Visual Culture of Art and Science, Royal Society (London), 1995 (Box 440, Folder 44)
    - Who is the Person of the Millennium/Century?, Boston, 1995 (Box 440, Folder 45)
    - Who Wants to be Jewish? Jewish Identity in a Secular Age, Wilna Center for Jewish Heritage (Box 440, Folder 46)
    - William W. Cook Lectures on American Institutions, University of Michigan (Ann Arbor), 1998 (Box 440, Folder 47)
    - Wittenberg Sesquicentennial Symposium, Wittenberg University, 1994 (Box 441, Folder 7)
    - Yaseen Lectures on Creativity, Neuberger Museum, 1986 (Box 440, Folder 48)
    - Lecture Posters (2 folders) (Flat-box 438, Folders 7-8)
    - Lecture Posters (Flat-box 438, Folder 10)
    - Lecture Posters (2 folders) (Flat-box 518, Folders 4-5)
  - Data
    - Data - Computer printouts (Carton 238)
    - Data - Computer printouts (Carton 239)
    - Data - Computer printouts (Carton 244)
    - Data - Computer printouts (Boxes 247-250)
    - Data - Computer printouts (Box 258)
    - Data - Computer printouts (Cartons 295-297)
    - Data - Computer printouts (Cartons 312 -314)
    - Data - Computer printouts (Carton 342)
    - Data - Computer printouts (Carton 358)
    - Data - Nassau Xerox Ramsey - Living & Fossil (Box 343, Folder 1)
    - Data - Inagua Data Sheets (Box 343, Folder 2)
    - Data - Andros, 1987 (Box 343, Folder 3)
    - Data - Sinistral Project - Conus Mediterraneus (Box 343, Folder 4)
    - Data (Box 343, Folder 5)
    - Data - D/DA (Box 343, Folder 6)
    - Data - Cerion: Trade Quotes Criteria/Some Data on Tape (Box 343, Folder 7)
    - Data - Turks and Caicos (Box 343, Folder 8)
    - Data - Inagua (Box 343, Folder 9)
    - Data - Eleuthera NOT for Agassizi Study (Box 344, Folder 1)
    - Data - Cat Island for Agassizi Study (Box 344, Folder 2)
    - Data - New Providence NOT for Agassizi Study (Box 344, Folder 3)
    - Data - Cat Island NOT for Agassizi Study (Box 344, Folder 4)
    - Data - Eleuthera for Agassizi Study (Box 344, Folder 5)
    - Data - New Providence for Agassizi Study (Box 344, Folder 6)
    - Data - Cat Island 2 (Box 344, Folder 7)
    - Data - Fossil Listing (Box 344, Folder 8)
    - Data - Sinistral Study (Box 344, Folder 9)
    - Data - Sinistral Snails (Box 344, Folder 10)